fronter.com 2018-10-05

# Privacy Policy - itslearning - Global

**Posted: 4 May 2018**  
**Last updated: 4 May 2018**

## INTRODUCTION

itslearning (“we”) is committed to keeping your data safe. Any time we collect or process your data, we’ll do so legally. That means that we will only process data with your explicit permission and/or for necessary marketing and sales communication. This page will explain, in some detail:

  * Who collects the data
  * What data we collect
  * How we collect data
  * Why we collect data
  * How we use the data
  * Data processors
  * Your data rights

While you’re on our site, we’ll collect and store information about you in accordance with this policy. If you don’t agree with this, please visit our [Cookie Policy](https://itslearning.com/global/cookie-policy) for information about how to turn tracking off, or, exit the site entirely – we won’t take it personally.

We are a global company, so when you provide us personal data, that data may be used, processed, or stored anywhere in the world, including in countries that have data protection laws that are different to the country in which you reside. However, itslearning has policies and procedures in place that are constructed to safeguard and ensure an equal level of protection is applied across the entire organization and in accordance with this Policy.

This Privacy Policy (which we’ll refer to as “Policy” going forward), describes practices with regards to our marketing websites (“website” going forward), e-mails, affiliates, virtual and in-person events, offline sales, and additional marketing and sales activities.

## WHO COLLECTS THE DATA

All data is collected on behalf of itslearning AS, Solheimsgaten 7D, 5058 Bergen, Norway and its subsidiaries. We can be contacted by email: [post@itslearning.com](mailto:post@itslearning.com) or via phone at +47 55 23 60 70.

Our DPO, John Arthur Berg can be contacted via email at [contact-dpo@itslearning.com](mailto:contact-dpo@itslearning.com), or by phone at + 47 55 23 60 70.

## WHAT DATA WE COLLECT

We will never collect data about you without clearly stating what information we are requesting and what we will use it for. This is the data we collect:

  * Your first and last name, e-mail address, phone number
  * Company information including name, physical address, size
  * Geographical location, IP address, including country, state or province
  * Behavioral or demographical information
  * Data from marketing opt-in lists, campaigns, surveys, or publicly available information
  * Collaboration information

## HOW WE COLLECT DATA

Through your interaction with us or use of this website, we may collect the following personal information that identifies you as an individual:

  * Information you provide through form submissions on our websites. This includes when you contact us, subscribe to our marketing communications, download collateral, register or attend an itslearning event or partner event, and purchase products or services.
  * Information you provide when applying for a job.
  * Information that you submit to us or itslearning employees when you want to engage in business or potential business with us.
  * Information you provide us through our website, in-personal conversations or events.
  * Information from surveys, reviews, or inquiries that you voluntarily take part in.
  * Information you submit to us via social media channels.

We don’t intentionally solicit, collect or process data for anybody under the age of 18. If it happens by accident, we delete it immediately.

We collect data via third-party advertisers, such as Google Adwords remarketing service. It could mean that we advertise to previous visitors who haven’t completed a task on our site, for example using the contact form to make an enquiry. This could be in the form of an advertisement on the Google search results page, or a site in the Google Display Network.

## WHY WE COLLECT DATA

We collect your data to better provide you information and determine whether our LMS would be a good fit for you. In those cases where we use legitimate interest as lawful basis for our data processing, we will always balance our interest with your right to data privacy.

The legitimate interest basis makes processing lawful only if it is necessary of the controller. It requires transparency and the successful outcome of a balancing test between your right to privacy and our interests. Transparency means it shall be clear to you which data is used and how it’s used. A balancing test requires us to take into consideration factors such as:

  * That our interest as controller is significant compared to the impact on your data privacy
  * That we only process what can reasonably be expected by you
  * That we cannot achieve the same by not processing the data

As such, our purposes are always legitimate, and the disadvantages to you are few.

These are our specific purposes for processing your data:

  * Identifying and targeting educational institutions that have an interest and need for a learning management system
  * Promoting our learning management system to interested potential customers
  * Nurturing relationships with interested potential customers, whether we initially encountered them via telephone, web or in-person.
  * Managing customer relationships, to better communicate any updates or changes they might be interested in

## HOW WE USE THE DATA

We only collect or process your data we are performing a contract, when we have consent, or when we have a legitimate interest.

Your **consent** must be clear, unambiguous and freely given. When we request information, we have to tell you what we’d like to know and why. **Legitimate interests** are uses that are necessary to provide a product or service, or those that could be reasonably expected by the person whose information is being collected.

If no activity, interest, intent or need can be identified within a 2-year period, we delete your data. Please note that third-party sites may retain it. The only time we will retain your personal information for longer than is outlined in this Policy is when it is required by law.

The chart below explains how we use the data collected through each of our channels, the purpose and the legal basis we have for doing so.

**How we collect data** | **Why we collect data** | **How we use the data** | **The legal basis for our use**  
---|---|---|---  
You fill out a form on our website, including those from Marketo, LiveChat, Google Forms, Typeform, Survey Monkey and Eventbrite. | Identifying and targeting educational institutions that have an interest and need for a learning management system. 

Nurturing relationships with interested potential customers.

Managing customer relationships, to better communicate any updates or changes they might be interested in.

| When you fill out a form, we let you know why and how we’ll use the data. 

This includes requests to contact us, subscribe to our marketing communications or newsletter, download collateral, register or attend an itslearning event or partner event, and purchase products or services, or identify a company’s need for an LMS.

| Consent  
We collect your information from a publicly available source (e.g. you have your contact information listed on your website.) | Identifying and targeting educational institutions that have an interest and need for a learning management system. | We use this information to ensure that the data we are processing of yours is correct and up to date, as well as to correctly profile whether you have potential, intent or a need to purchase an LMS. | Legitimate Interest  
You contact us via our LiveChat form. | Nurturing relationships with interested potential customers 

Managing customer relationships, to better communicate any updates or changes they might be interested in

| We track your on-site behavior to better answer your questions, as well as to notify you that a representative is available should you wish to engage, make product inquiries or further a purchase. | Consent  
We’ve partnered with a related company to create a cross-promotional opportunity. | Identifying and targeting educational institutions that have an interest and need for a learning management system. | We use this data to better identify customers who might have a potential need or interest in an LMS. | Legitimate Interest  
We talk to you at an event or tradeshow. | Nurturing relationships with interested potential customers. 

Managing customer relationships, to better communicate any updates or changes they might be interested in.

| We use your information to build relationships, determine whether you may have a need or intent to purchase an LMS, and to obtain explicit consent to be added to our marketing distribution email list for further nurturing. | Legitimate Interest  
We communicate with you via our social media channels. | Nurturing relationships with interested potential customers. 

Managing customer relationships, to better communicate any updates or changes they might be interested in.

| We build brand awareness, and link you to information on our website that we believe may prove useful. | Legitimate Interest  
You sign up for a particular piece of email marketing. | Promoting our learning management system to interested potential customers. 

Managing customer relationships, to better communicate any updates or changes they might be interested in.

| itslearning has a legitimate interest to send singular emails for one intended purpose, or at the request, or knowledge of the recipient. | Legitimate Interest  
You sign up to be on our marketing distribution list. | Promoting our learning management system to interested potential customers. 

Managing customer relationships, to better.

| itslearning will explicitly ask if a prospect would like to be added to the distribution list to receive marketing communication on products, services, topics that may be of interest to them. | Consent  
One of our representatives talks to you in person, email, via drop-in or at a networking event. | Nurturing relationships with interested potential customers 

Managing customer relationships, to better communicate any updates or changes they might be interested in

| We follow up on high-level marketing activity and buyer behavior in order to reach out, establish contact, create or foster a relationship, and follow up for the purposes of driving sales and revenue. | Legitimate Interest  
  
## DATA PROCESSORS

Data processors are third parties with whom we have contracted to assist in our communication to users, customers, partners and prospects. They are not allowed to process your personal information unless we instruct them to do so. They will not share your personal information with any other organization. They will secure and retain your data for the period we specify. In those cases where the data resides in a non-EU country, we indicate the location next to the processor’s name.

**Salesforce (US)**  
We use Salesforce as our CRM system and our main tool for communication with our partners, customers and prospects. We have Binding Corporate Rules that ensure that any data transfer has an adequate level of data protection.

**Marketo (US)**  
Marketo is our Marketing automation software and is used to communicate to prospects, users and customers. We have Standard Contractual Clauses with Marketo, which ensure that any data transfer has an adequate level of data protection.

**Live Chat (US)**  
LiveChat powers the chatting service on our websites. Information collected by LiveChat will be retained for 24 months. We have signed Standard Contractual Clauses which ensure that any data transfer has an adequate level of data protection.

**Survey Monkey (US)**  
Survey Monkey is used as our survey tool. We use this for general surveys and to plan and evaluate events. We have signed Standard Contractual Clauses which ensure that any data transfer has an adequate level of data protection.

**Adobe Sign (US)**  
Adobe Sign is used to digitally sign documents. Adobe will store some information about the signed documents or signature/the signing and the event in addition to an audit trail. We have signed Standard Contractual Clauses which ensure that any data transfer has an adequate level of data protection.

**Google Analytics  
**

Google Analytics is used to analyse the use of our website. Our analytics service provider generates statistical and other information about website use by means of cookies. The information generated relating to our website is aggregated and used to create trending reports about the use of our website. It is used to improve how itslearning.com functions and performs.

**Consultants**  
We use several consulting companies in our day-to-day operations. They have all signed a confidentiality and non-disclosure agreement and a data processing agreement.

  * [Pedowitz Group](http://www.pedowitzgroup.com/) (US), a marketing technology consultancy
  * [Jaroop](https://www.jaroop.com/) (US), a web development consultancy
  * [Amesto](https://www.amesto.com/), a translation service provider

## YOUR DATA RIGHTS

When it comes to your personal data, you have rights:

  * You have the right to know whether we have your information.
  * You have the right to access any information we have about you.
  * You have the right to correct or update your information.
  * You have the right to unsubscribe from our marketing materials, whenever you choose.
  * You have the right to tell us not to process your data for marketing.
  * You have the right to withdraw consent to use your information. (This withdrawal does not retroactively affect the lawfulness of any processing, nor does it affect processing that does not rely on consent.)
  * You have the right to talk about your personal data with our Data Protection Officer.
  * You have the right to lodge a complaint if you think we’ve mishandled your data.
  * You have the right to make us delete any information you’ve consented to share.

In some cases these rights are subject to certain conditions and limitations. If you would like to learn more about these rights please contact our Data Protection Officer.

If you want to exercise any of these rights, you have a number of different ways to do so. You can:

  * Contact our [DPO](mailto:contact-dpo@itslearning.com) via email
  * To unsubscribe [click here](http://info.itslearning.net/UnsubscribeForm.html)
  * Lodge a complaint with a [supervisory authority](http://ec.europa.eu/newsroom/article29/item-detail.cfm?item_id=612080)

All requests will be processed within one month.

[Click here](https://itslearning.com/global/wp-content/uploads/sites/20/2017/11/privacy_policy_itslearning-app.pdf) to read the privacy policy for the itslearning App

**Previous version(s):**
